# Samuel Atkins

Software Engineer sjatkins12@gmail.com | +33 0615863193 github.com/sjatkins12 | linkedin.com/in/sam-atkins

#### **PROFILE**

Passionate programmer with professional experience as an engineer solving complex real world problems by bringing products from ideas into designs into shipped solutions. My excitement for programming bleeds into my work and can be seen in the practices I adhere to and in the formation of my contributions. I take pride in my everyday work and I enjoy helping others do the same.

## WORK EXPERIENCE \_\_\_\_\_

Paris, FR Ubble.ai 11/2019 - 6/2020

Full Stack Software Engineer

Startup Development Team of 5 Engineers on AWS-Postgres-Django-React Stack

- Contributed to building a Kubernetes ISTIO operator to manage releases in multiple deployed environments
- Built standalone micro services

**Tesla Motors** Palo Alto, CA

Software Engineer Intern (Autopilot)

1/2019 - 6/2019

- Computer Vision Infrastructure and Frameworks team
- Worked across autopilot teams to support computer vision pipelines
- Automated local ECU testing to improve developers experience with ARM environment
- Improved CI build queues by implementing a workerpool with a callback interface

#### **Optum / UnitedHealth Group**

Boston, MA 5/2018 - 8/2018

Technology Development Program

- Developed machine learning model to classify tasks given to software teams
- Predicted the Time to Build of software features from historical development data

#### **PROJECTS**

### N-Puzzle - C++

Designed and built a pathfinding algorithm to solve a classical N-Puzzle in the minimum number of moves. Algorithm also focused on minimizing auxiliary data, without redundancy.

## IRC & FTP - C

Created ftp and irc server and client programs, with an asynchronous I/O server. I implemented my own class structure to simulate an object oriented language with C.

#### Corewar - C

Designed a Virtual Machine to act as a battlefield where multiple processes compete over a shared memory space.

### **Worker Server** - Go

Designed a general http server that can distribute tasks. Easily extensible for any microservice architecture.

#### 42sh - C

A complete shell that handles UI, syntax, pipelined execution and job control.

#### Malloc - C

Recoding of the classic functions malloc(), realloc(), calloc() and free(). Built with the focus on minimizing system calls.

## EDUCATION \_\_\_\_\_

#### **42 Silicon Valley**

Fremont, CA

9/2017 - 9/2018

MS Software Engineering equivalent

Starfleet curriculum; One year intensive (80+ hours per week) Software Engineering Program

• Programming languages: C; C++; Python

## **Pennsylvania State University**

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science Curriculum

**University Park, PA** 9/2015 - 6/2017

### Coursework:

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Object Oriented Design
- Database Design

- Computer Architecture
- Discrete Mathematics

## **SKILLS** \_

- C
- C++

- Go
- Python